<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Zellij</title>
    <link>https://zellij-org.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Zellij</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://zellij-org.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Zellij hits beta!</title>
      <link>https://zellij-org.github.io/news/beta/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zellij-org.github.io/news/beta/</guid>
      <description>After long months of work by a dedicated team of enthusiasts, today we are proud to announce the release of the beta version of Zellij!
Zellij is a terminal workspace and multiplexer written in Rust, aiming to become a general purpose application development platform in the future.
 Why is Zellij different? Zellij is constantly evolving, and even in this early stage it still shines. Including the basic features of a terminal multiplexer with some fundamental infrastructure changes, as well as some extra goodies included from the get-go.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Zellij</title>
      <link>https://zellij-org.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zellij-org.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Zellij is a terminal workspace. It has the base functionality of a terminal multiplexer (similar to tmux or screen) but includes many built-in features that would allow users to extend it and create their own personalized environment.
Split the terminal into different panes and tabs Like other multiplexers, Zellij allows users to split their terminal into different panes and tabs:
 Layout Engine Zellij includes a layout engine, allowing users to define a map of panes in a yaml file and load it when they start the app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Screenshots</title>
      <link>https://zellij-org.github.io/screenshots/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zellij-org.github.io/screenshots/</guid>
      <description>Default interface with a few panes and tabs  Zellij with the Strider plugin Strider is a ranger clone and comes built-in with Zellij. To run, load its layout with:
zellij --layout strider
 </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
