<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Zellij</title>
    <link>https://zellij.dev/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Zellij</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://zellij.dev/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Zellij 0.25.0: floating panes, tmux mode and more!</title>
      <link>https://zellij.dev/news/floating-panes-tmux-mode/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zellij.dev/news/floating-panes-tmux-mode/</guid>
      <description>We just released Zellij 0.25.0, which adds a few features we are very excited about!
The new release is already available through crates.io with a cargo install zellij, a prebuilt binary can be downloaded directly from the release page, or you can check our third party release page to see if it&amp;rsquo;s already available for your distro.
So what&amp;rsquo;s new?
Floating Panes Floating panes can stack and move freely. Their visibility can be toggled on and off with ctrl-p + w (if there are no open floating panes, toggling their visibility on will open a new one).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Share your Terminal with Multiple Cursors</title>
      <link>https://zellij.dev/news/multiplayer-sessions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zellij.dev/news/multiplayer-sessions/</guid>
      <description>We just released Zellij 0.23.0, which adds collaboration features to our terminal multiplexer.
This solution allows multiple users to be attached to the same Zellij session and each have their own cursor. The cursors appear in different colors, giving a Google-docs like experience in the terminal and allowing users to be focused not only on different tabs, but on different panes in the same tab. That way they can see each other type in real time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zellij 0.16.0: new UI, many bugfixes and more!</title>
      <link>https://zellij.dev/news/new-ui/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zellij.dev/news/new-ui/</guid>
      <description>Zellij 0.16.0 is out!
You can download a prebuilt binary in the above link or install it through cargo with cargo install zellij (unaffiliated releases might also be available for your distribution or in homebrew).
We&amp;rsquo;re constantly working on improving Zellij and releasing new features and bug fixes. Today, on this last day of August, we&amp;rsquo;re releasing a large version with so many fixes and improvements we felt it warranted a post with a walkthrough.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zellij: a Rusty terminal workspace releases a beta</title>
      <link>https://zellij.dev/news/beta/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zellij.dev/news/beta/</guid>
      <description>After long months of work by a dedicated team of enthusiasts, today we are proud to announce the release of the beta version of Zellij!
Zellij is a terminal workspace and multiplexer written in Rust, aiming to become a general purpose application development platform in the future.
 How to install? Download a prebuilt binary for linux or macOS.
Or install with cargo:
cargo install zellij Why is Zellij different? Zellij is constantly evolving, and even in this early stage it still shines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Zellij</title>
      <link>https://zellij.dev/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zellij.dev/about/</guid>
      <description>Zellij is a terminal workspace. It has the base functionality of a terminal multiplexer (similar to tmux or screen) but includes many built-in features that would allow users to extend it and create their own personalized environment.
Split the terminal into different panes and tabs Like other multiplexers, Zellij allows users to split their terminal into different panes and tabs:
 Layout Engine Zellij includes a layout engine, allowing users to define a map of panes in a yaml file and load it when they start the app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Screenshots</title>
      <link>https://zellij.dev/screenshots/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zellij.dev/screenshots/</guid>
      <description>Default interface with a few panes and tabs  Zellij with the Strider plugin Strider is a ranger clone and comes built-in with Zellij. To run, load its layout with:
zellij --layout strider
 Basic multiplexer functionality demonstration  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
